# MECHATRONICS ENGINEER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (PYTHON, JAVASCRIPT)

Aghar Mohammad Al-Masri Iordanian

Date & Place of Birth: July 23rd, 1986, Jordan

Married

Tel: +962792938483

E-mail: aghar 4@hotmail.com

Website: <a href="https://agharweb-54fc277bc896.herokuapp.com">https://agharweb-54fc277bc896.herokuapp.com</a>



#### **SUMMARY**

Mechanical/Mechatronics engineer with 9+ years of experience in the pharmaceutical and food industries. I have worked in quality assurance, instrumentation, equipment qualification and validation, metrology, calibration and test report assessment of various products in the mechanical, electrical and chemical sectors. I also have good background in risk management. I am looking for a working environment that encourages autonomy, facilitates mastery and provides purpose.

I am currently learning on my own to pursue a career in Software Development.

**STRENGTHS:** Supportive, Reliable and Patient, Imaginative and Observant, Loyal and Hard-Working.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & TRAINING

# <u>Jordan Standards & Metrology Organization (Jul 2016 – Present)</u>

Duties & Departments joined:

- <u>Market Surveillance</u> to prevent trade of products not complying with Jordanian Standards & Technical Regulations.
- <u>Border Control</u> (of imports) to ensure compliance with Technical Regulations and Standards.
- <u>Engineering Laboratories</u>: Performing photoelectrical testing of Luminaires. And preparing technical documents to be used in the household electrical appliances testing lab according to the IEC 60335 standards.

2

• <u>Risk Management Unit</u>: worked in the system that deals with complying importers.

### Rieckermann GmbH. Amman - Jordan (Dec 2012 - Apr 2014)

Scope of work: Sterile Pharmaceutical Plant Setup for Tabuk Pharma Co., Dammam – KSA: Preparing Qualification Protocols and documents for various equipments and Machines.

#### TRAINING COURSES

- Programming (Getting Started with Python) & Python Data Structures. From Coursera-University of Michigan. With Certificates. Aug-2023.
- Training on Safety of Electrical and Gas Appliances EU expert at JSMO.
- Safety of Electrical Appliances (IEC 60335-1) JSMO.
- PLC Troubleshooting (SIEMENS SIMATIC S7 ST-7STOE)—Jordan Engineers Association.
- AC Inverters (FRENIC-Mini) Jordan Engineers Association.
- Electrical Installation (Experimental) Nawabegh Al-Handasah, Amman.
- University Training (8 weeks) Jordan Cement Factories (LAFARGE), Amman.

#### **EDUCATION**

Feb 2005 - Feb 2010

BA. in Mechanical Engineering, Mechatronics branch. Jordan University of Science and Technology.

## REFERENCES

- Majdi Ayoub, Validation & Quality manager at Rieckermann GmbH. Tel: +962799700021.
- Hosam Hamdan, Electronics expert (Royal Jordanian Air Force.) Tel: +962795719855.
- Hussein Hawajreh, Head of Risk Management Unit. Tel: +962799031332.

#### LANGUAGES

- Arabic (Mother Language)
- English (Professional)
- German (B1)